翻譯：閒著沒事幹的MT 隨便改
人類如何瞭解未知
How does one come to know The Unknowable?
人類需要什麼技能
What faculties must a man possess?
自從人類發現鯨油
Since it was discovered that whale oil
可以以前所未有的方式點亮我們的城市
could light our cities in ways never achieved before,
全世界需求量暴漲
it created global demand.
使人類向開始向
It had pushed man to venture further and further
海洋更深處冒險
into The Deep, Blue Unknown.
我們不知道海洋的深度
We know not its depths,
也不瞭解海洋裏的生物
nor the host of creatures that live there.
怪物是否真的存在
Monsters, are they real?
或者這些故事只是讓我們對海洋隱藏的秘密有所敬畏
Or do the stories exist only to make us respect the sea's dark secret?
楠塔基特島 馬薩諸塞州 1850年二月
這個問題使我即苦惱又興奮
The question both vexes and excites me,
也是我再次向您寫信請求一次會面的原因
and is the reason I've written you a second time to request a meeting.
一次和您交談的機會 先生
A conversation with you, Sir,
我相信這會對我將要寫的小說有很大幫助
I believe will serve me well for the novel I intend to write,
小說暫且名為 白鯨記
currently entitled Moby Dick
我期望您能考慮我的提議
I hope you will reconsider my offer.
未知 我的想像力始終想冒險的地方
The Unknown, that is where my imagination yearns to venture.
始終折磨我的問題是
And so, the question plagues me still:
人類如何才能探索未知
How does a man come to know The Unknowable?
此致 赫爾曼·梅爾維爾
Sincerely, Herman Melville.
我們打烊了
We're closed!
8點後不接客
No borders after eight o'clock.
你居然來了
You came.
親愛的 有人來看你
There's someone here for you, My Love.
湯姆·尼克森
Tom Nickerson?
赫爾曼·梅爾維爾
Herman Melville.
我們收到了你的來信
We received your letter.
你要麼走投無路要麼是個傻子大老遠跑來楠塔基特
You're either a desperate man or a fool to come all the way to Nantucket.
我的提議還在
Well, my offer still stands.
3個月的住宿換一晚的交談
Three months'lodgings for a single night's talk.
這是我所有的錢了
It's all I have in the world.
但我更願意看作是一次投資
But I'd prefer to think of it as an investment.
我想要你告訴我
I want you to tell me what happened...
埃塞克斯號發生了什麼
to the Essex.
你覺得發生了什麼
Well,what do you think happened?
有傳言埃塞克斯號
There are rumblings,rumors that the Essex...
你想要什麼 期望聽到什麼故事
What do you want?What story do you expect to hear?
白鯨的故事
That of The Whale.
埃塞克斯號擱淺了 有完整的報告
The Essex ran aground, there was a full inquiry.
我覺得那份報告不是事實全部
I believe the inquiry was less than truthful.
滾出去
Get out.
先生 你是埃塞克斯號上唯一的倖存者
You are the last survivor or the Essex, Sir.
如果你不說出來 誰還能講出事實
If you won't talk, who will?
你沒聽見我的話嗎 出去
You do not hear me, leave now.
你不能走 拜託 就一會兒  他沒心情談
- You mustn't go, please, just take a minute... - He's in no mind to talk, and
我不是大老遠來就是為了被羞辱和浪費時間
I haven't come all this way to be humiliated and waste my time.
拜託了 梅爾維爾 先生
Please, Mr. Melville,
他從來不跟別人談論埃塞克斯號 包括我 從不
he won't talk about the Essex to me, to anyone... never has... never.
我一點都不瞭解他
I don't know anything about him.
他的精神在受折磨 需要救贖
His soul is... in torment, and in need of confession.
拜託了 請讓我和他談 拜託了
Please, just let me talk to him... please.
親愛的
Love,
我覺得和這個年輕人談會對你有好處
I believe it would do you good to talk to the man.
不
No!
你聽著
You listen well!
你酗酒要死的時候誰撐著這個家了
Who holds this place together while you drink yourself to death?
你必須和這個年輕人談
You WILL talk with this man, as much as is necessary...
才能保住你的錢
to keep the money.
你知道我們的處境 湯姆
You know our circumstances, Tom.
我只說必要的
Only as much as is necessary.
我去拿威士忌
I'll get whiskey.
我忘了在信裏提到我曾經是一名捕鯨手
I neglected to mention it in my letter, but I was a whaler once.
有過一次出航 新手
One trip. I mean... green hand.
那麼你應該都經歷過了
So, you've seen it all.
我妻子讀過你的書
My wife read your books.
她很喜歡 很高興聽到
- She enjoyed them. - Happy to hear it.
銷量很好 但我估計這個故事
They had good sales, but I think that THIS story
甚至能超過我銷量不錯的第一部小說
could surpass even the success of my first novel... which did quite well.
又一個你的航海軼事
Another of your seafaring yarns.
你聽說過霍索恩嗎 梅爾維爾先生
Have you read Hawthorne, Mr. Melville?
當下有一名作家 一個大作家
Now, there's a writer, a great writer.
他是的
He is.
但他不在這兒 因為我自己的原因
But he is not here, and I am...
我在這兒
for my own particular reasons.
我會告訴你埃塞克斯號 我相信你會失望的
I'll tell you of the Essex, I believe you will be disappointed,
但我說的每個字都是真實的
but every word I say will be true.
埃塞克斯號的故事就是兩個男人的故事
The story of the Essex is the story of two men...
喬治·波拉德船長
Captain George Pollard,
和他大副 歐文·查斯
and his first mate, Owen Chase.
歐文 你不能遲到
Owen, you don't want to be late.
我會到那兒的 再說了 不能讓我們的女兒睡在破陋的房子裏對吧
I'll be there, besides, can't have our daughter sleeping under a leaky roof, can we?
你為什麼那麼肯定是女兒
What makes you so sure it's a girl?
肯定是的 她會提醒我你這麼固執為什麼我還是愛你
Well, it has to be, so she can remind me why I have to love you, and you being stubborn.
如果是女兒她會更像你而不是我
If it's to to be a daughter she'll be a version of you, not me.
金髮而且一心想征服世界
Blond locks and determined to conquer the world.
我想過了今天你會用那件外套換一套制服
I suppose after today you'll be tradin' in that tunic for a uniform.
沒錯 終於能離開這破地方去賺個區艾瑟 船長該住的房子了
That's right, finally out of this patch of dirt for a captain's house in Quaise.
我不想住在周邊都是古板的鄰居的房子裏
I don't need one of those houses in town with stuffy neighbors.
這裏有足夠供我們一家三口居住的地方
There's plenty room here for the three of us.
有時候你的溫情真讓人受不了
Ya know, sometimes your kind heart and good nature is just unbearable.
去做你的船長吧
Go get your captaincy.
- 你下注 1美元9分
- What's your bid? - One ninety.
我用2美元買到了一千加侖
I've got a thousand gallons at two dollars!
我佔40份
I'll take 40 shares.
賣家 賣家 在這
Seller, seller, over here!
克雷斯拉回來了1600桶
Criterion's back with a fine haul, 1600 barrels.
倫敦市場新紀錄 50磅銀器換燈芯
A new record, 50 pounds Sterling for headmatter on the London market.
早上好 查斯先生
Good morning Mr. Chase.
馬森先生 請進
- Mr. Mason. - Come in, please.
我的合夥人 本傑明·福勒
My partner, Benjamin Fuller.
早上好 先生 請坐
- Good morning, Sir. - Do sit down.
查斯先生 我們希望你知道我們對你
Mr. Chase, I do hope you realize how satisfied we are
為我們多年的工作有多麼滿意
with the work you've done for us over the years.
謝謝 先生
Oh, thank you, Sir.
我們其中一艘船 埃塞克斯號
And one of our ships, the Essex
已經花大價錢修整好準備出海了
has just be refitted at great expense and is to go to sea.
因為在她身上花了大價錢
Now, having made such an investment in her,
我們希望確保她在最適合的人手裏
we want to be sure she's in the best possible hands.
所以
So...
我們很高興邀請你成為這艘船的
it gives us great pleasure to offer you a position aboard her...
大副
as first mate.
大副 是的
- As first mate? - Uh-hum.
馬森先生 你許諾過我上次出航帶回來1500桶的話
Mr. Mason, you... you promised me command of a ship after my last voyage when
會讓我當一艘船的船長 你保證過的
I brought you back 1500 barrels, do you remember? You gave me your word.
那個承諾要推遲了
That promise must now be deferred.
像別人一樣我們最近行情不好
Like everyone else we've had a mean time recently.
我看不是
Well, never on my watch.
楠塔基特主宰了全球市場 這點不能變
Nantucket now dominates the world market, that must not change.
沒有時間來試驗
This is no time for experimentation.
埃塞克斯號必須由喬治·波拉德指揮
The Essex will be captained by George Pollard,
偉大的捕鯨家族的後裔
scion of a great whaling family.
他的父親也是我們的老主顧
His father also happens to be our patron.
血統 查斯先生 你可以有出色的航海技能
Blood, Mr. Chase, you can have all the voyages under your belt you want
但血統還是更重要
but blood will always win out.
但是血統不會幫你的船裝滿油回來 馬森先生
Yes, well, blood's not gonna fill the ship with oil, Mr. Mason.
要成功指揮船 船長需要被人尊重 如果別人不尊重他怎麼辦
To successfully command, a captain needs respect, now, what if the men don't respect him?
你就要確保別人尊重他
You will make sure that they do.
再見 先生們
Good day, Gentlemen.
我理解你的失落
I understand your disappointment.
所以
So...
115金幣
A one-fifteenth lay.
我從來沒有給新長官支付過這麼多
And that's more than I've ever paid any first officer.
如果你帶回來2000桶油 我向你保證
And if you bring back 2000 barrels of oil, I'll give you my word,
下次你就會是船長
next time you WILL have your captaincy.
你之前給過我保證來 馬森先生
You've given me your word before, Mr. Mason.
這次我需要書面保證
So, this time I'll take it in writing.
波拉德船長 我們和查斯先生達成了協議
Captain Pollard, we've just had a most agreeable conversation with Mr. Chase,
他會很榮幸服務於您
who'd be honored to serve under you.
我很高興聽到
I'm glad to hear it.
現在我得照顧個沒經驗的
Now I'm to babysit a greenhorn.
一個含著他媽的金勺長大的船長了
Some cheerless Nantucket born with a damned silver spoon in his mouth.
我真應該當面拒絕
I should have thrown their offer back in their faces.
為什麼 你已經拿到書面承諾了
Why? You now have the offer of command in writing.
騙子的世界什麼都是假的 即使是書面承諾
Yes, well, a liar's word is worthless, even ON paper.
你知道即使你是商人我還是會愛上你的
You know I'd love you just as much if you were a merchant captain?
你不能離開兩年之久
And you wouldn't be gone for two years.
我不會離開兩年之久的
I won't be gone two years.
貝德福德家的捕鯨人上周回來了 離開了有三年
A Bedford whaler came back last week was gone three.
她失去了兩個男人 而且驚魂落魄
She lost two men and still with her hull half empty.
他們是貝德福德家 沒有我在
Well, they were from Bedford and they didn't have me aboard.
婊子養的
Son of a bitch!
我要指揮我自己的船
I will captain my own ship...
一艘捕鯨船
a whaling ship.
靠他們我們只能永遠在這個鬼地方
Up to them all we'd ever have is a patch of dirt
我不會讓這發生的 佩吉
and that's not going to happen, Peggy.
你父親也是這麼說的 你不能這麼說
Those'd be your father's words, not yours.
他的話怎麼了
What's wrong with his words?
他想要為家人為自己爭取
He wanted things for his family, for himself.
他是個夢想家 歐文 是的 他是
- He was a dreamer, Owen - Yes, he was.
夢想大海 不帶那些廢物們出海
Dreamed of the sea and never got to sea with men like them.
至少他看到了他的孩子出生
At least he got to see his children born.
我只能幹這些
It's all I know.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我嫁給了一個捕鯨人
I married a whaleman.
我會盡快回來 我發誓
I'll come back as quick as the sun is night, I swear.
一定要回來 向我保證
Please come back... promise me.
我已經向你發誓了 你還要我保證
I already swore to you, now you want me to promise, too.
我保證
I promise.
孩子 跟你說句話
Son, a word with you.
當船長 你不能當他們的朋友 你是他們的長官
To be a captain, you cannot be a friend, you are their superior.
別忘了這點 讓別人記住這點
Never forget that, never let THEM forget that.
謝謝
Thank you, son.
你的曾祖父和其他人創立了這個行業
Your great-grandfather and a few others created this industry.
沒有我們 沒有你們 世界將會陷入黑暗
Without us, without you, the world plunges into darkness.
我希望能讓家族名譽生輝 先生
I hope to bring honor to the Pollard family name, Sir.
啊 上帝創造了巨大的鯨 體長無比的神奇怪物
Thou didst, O Lord, create the mighty whale, That wondrous monster of a mighty length;
頭碩身龐尾又闊 無邊雄力人難度
Beyond conception his unmeasured strength.
恆古上帝宥永生 吾儕荏弱落凡塵
But, everlasting God, thou dost ordain that we, poor feeble mortals
妻兒一家須偷生
should engage ourselves, our wives and children to maintain,
賴此巨物維生存
This dreadful monster with a martial rage.
啊 上帝 用您的榮耀之光照亮這些男人
O Father, grant that your glorious light shine on these men,
保佑他們豐收的航程
and assure them a prosperous voyage,
保佑他們安全歸來
that they may return SAFELY unto the womb ship.
楠塔基特的白鯨油
So that the white whales of Nantucket whale oil
可以繼續照亮我們的房屋
may continue to keep light in our homes,
照亮我們的街道 為工業機器提供燃料
city streets safe from sin in the night, fuel the machines of industry,
推動我們偉大的國家前進
drive our great nation forward,
我們文明種族進步 我們祈禱
as our noble species evolves. In Your name, we pray.
現在是幾月
So, what month is this?
年末了 我們是最後一批出海的船隻了
Oh, late in the year, we were one of the last ships to go out.
也是為什麼我和我朋友巴爾齊萊有臥鋪
Which is why my friend Barzillai and I got a berth.
聽著 我當時14歲
Look, I was fourteen... fourteen.
尼克森 別站著 幹活
Nickerson, you're standin' around, boy! Move!
第一次出海 很害怕 更害怕顯露出來
First time at sea, scared, more scared to show it.
巴爾齊萊當時17歲
Barzillai was seventeen.
在碼頭長大的孤兒都等不及被別人視作大人
Orphans, grew up on the wharf, both in a hurry to be called men.
你們慢騰騰幹嘛 裝船 快 快
What are you all guys waiting for? Get it aboard! C'mon! Haul away...!
他們戴的是飾針是什麼
What are those pins they're wearing?
那些是白鯨徽章 湯姆斯
Those are whale pins, Thomas.
我怎麼才能得到一個
How do I get one of them?
你得用長矛刺殺一頭白鯨
Well, you've gotta thrust a killing lance.
那是世界上最大的怪物
The largest beast ever to breathe on the earth.
尼克森 把那綠色的東西給邦德先生
Nickerson, get the green stuff to Mr. Bond.
快點 媽的
Make it quick, damn it.
我總有一天會有一堆那東西
I shall have twelve of those one day.
把它們放到匣子裏
Put 'em on the Grandira casket.
你也上船就說明一件事
Well, well, you being on board means only one thing.
是啊 這船上至少有一人明白歐文·查斯是誰
Yep! At least there's one person on this ship who knows the truth about Owen Chase.
不 可惜其他的船都已經滿員了
No, but all the other ships have already crewed up.
不不 我洗心革面了 歐文 問題是你呢
No, no, I'm a reformed man, Owen, the question is are YOU?
別告訴我花花公子馬修戒酒了
Don't tell me Matthew Joy has put down the bottle.
我有罪 歐文·查斯能消消他的壞脾氣了嗎
I have sinned. Has Owen Chase put down his temper?
平靜的像教堂
Serene as the Church.
照我看來
I'll believe THAT when I see it.
考慮到我們的船長 我覺得你只能平靜一小會兒
Given our captain I'll give your serenity about 48 hours.
祝你好運
Good luck.
波拉德 喬治·波拉德 歐文·查斯
- Pollard, George Pollard. - Owen Chase.
查斯 你父親的名字對嗎 對 是的
- Chase, your father's name, isn't it? - Yes, it is.
馬上他要離開島一段時間而我舒適得待在家
Very shortly he will be off island for some time and I'll be very much at home.
我要說 我有點意外 通常船長可以選擇自己的大副
I say, I was surprised, normally a captain gets to choose his first mate.
如果是有經驗的船長的話 是的
An experienced captain, yes.
當人 你可以理解老頭的意思
Of course, you can understand from the owners' point of view,
他們想讓自己的財產在適合的人手裏
they wanted to put their investments in the hands of men.
確實
Indeed.
他們也許想要多些保障
They probably wanted a little extra reassurance, that's all.
看著點我 如果我做錯什麼了告訴我
Well, DO keep an eye on me, let me know if I'm doing anything wrong.
我不會遲疑的 船長
I'd have it not other way, Captain.
起錨
Shore up the anchor.
起風了 頂部橫桿放下了嗎 好
- Head's in the wind, is the top rail off? - Aye.
克拉德 掌舵 好
- Collard, Take the helm! - Aye!
花花公子 揚帆
Mr. Joy, make sail.
科爾 查普爾 守在起錨器旁
Mr. Cole, Mr. Chappel, stand by this anchor!
查普爾 掌舵
Mr. Chappel, take the helm!
為什麼帆布還沒有鬆開
Boyd! Why aren't those braces laid out?
打開帆 媽的
Set the sail, god damn it!
跑開
Heading to scram.
船長 注意頭上 後面 船長
- Captain! Heads up! - Behind you head, Captain!
怎麼了 謝潑德 帆布纏住了 長官
- What happened, Mr. Sheppard? - The jalousie felled the sheet, Sir.
帆布纏住了 查斯 他辦不到
- The jalousie's jammed! - Chase, she still won't clear!
當心
Watch your step!
帆布 歐文
It's the jalousie, Owen!
走開
Stand clear!
幹的漂亮 查斯
Nice piece of work, Mr. Chase!
如果兩周內能到佛得角
If we make Cape Verdes in the next 2 weeks we'll
我們有很大幾率能按時到太平洋
have a decent chance of reaching the Pacific on schedule.
玉米棒 查斯
Corn, Mr. Chase?
不需要 謝謝 從來不喜歡
No, thank you, Sir, never did have much of a taste for it.
太怪了
That's odd.
你爸在科德角是種玉米的吧 是的
- So, your father grew corn on Cape Cod. - That's right, he did.
你也猜到了 我那時天天吃這個吃膩了
As you can imagine, I suddenly grew tired of eating it every day.
種玉米 秋葵 大豆 然後他進了監獄
Corn, okra, beans, I believe? Before he went to jail.
花花公子 聽起來熟悉嗎
Are you familiar with this story, Mr. Joy?
你知道查斯是因為他的父親進監獄才變成孤兒的嗎
Were you aware that Mr. Chase was effectively orphaned due to his father's incarceration?
我們都有不同的經歷
Well, we all have our paths to sea.
所以還是不要問太多問題為好
That's a motive to not ask too many questions.
一定不容易吧
Can't have been easy though, yet...
楠塔基特最偉大的航海家族收留你
You had Nantucket's great seafaring family to adopt you.
很久沒有楠塔基特人稱呼我陸人
This is far from the first time I've been called a landsman...
或者提醒我不是他們一家人了
or off-islander by some Nantucket reminding me how I am NOT part of their family.
請允許我 船長 我要去分配捕鯨船和值班了
Now, if the captain will excuse me, there are whale boats and watches to assign.
不 船長 滴酒不沾
- No, Sir, not for me. - Not a drop?
不 船長 就像我說的 有時候少問問題更好
No, Sir, like I said, sometimes the fewer questions one asks, the better.
花花公子 這有個漂亮姑娘
That's a gorgeous girl, Mr. Joy.
遠東的鯨骨上刻的
Region of move me that, carved from a Far East whalebone.
不許碰
No touching!
我一直以為你已經結婚了
I always thought you were married anyway.
是的 但看她
I am, and there she is.
這是她的鼻子
Well, that's her nose anyway.
恭喜 女士們
Congratulations, ladies.
今天啟航幹的不錯
That was a fine job trimin' sails today.
我從來沒有過這麼一群捕鯨人
A sorrier pack of deck-whalers I don't think I've ever seen.
查普爾 長官
- Mr. Chappel. - Sir.
船長魚叉手
Captain's harpooner.
勞倫斯 你做我的 遵命 長官
- Mr. Lawrence, you'll be mine. - Aye, Sir.
彼得森 二副的魚叉手
And Mr. Peterson, second mate's harpooner.
遵命 長官
Aye, Sir.
一船上六人 首要一點要警覺
There'll be six men to a boat, first rules in the row, six bells sharp.
我們還沒到哈利法克斯以東 長官
We're not even east of Halifax, Sir.
你叫什麼 克芬 亨利·克芬
- What's your name? - Coffin, Henry Coffin.
他是船長的表弟 長官
He's the Captain's cousin, Sir.
克芬先生 你覺得一頭白鯨會知道自己在哈利法克斯以東嗎
Well, well, Mr. Coffin, do you think a whale knows it's east of Halifax?
我不知道你們原來是誰 或者怎麼來的
I don't know who all of you are, or how you got here,
你們中一些人可能甚至是重犯 在隱藏或者逃亡
Some of you probably have felonies, or are hidin' or on the run.
沒關係 我不關心 我對你們的要求只有一個
That's fine, I don't give a damn, but we interred you for just one thing...
只有一個 就是鯨油
and one thing only, and that is whale oil.
我要裝滿2000桶油並盡快回家
I intend to fill our 2000 barrels and be home as quickly as possible.
即使天氣好而且沒有鯨出沒 克芬先生
And even when the weather is fine and there ARE no whales, Mr. Coffin,
我們會放下船練習如何捕鯨
we will lower the boats and practice all maneuvers necessary in a capture of a whale.
誰要是想偷懶就自己游回家 明白嗎
And any man who is idle will find himself swimmin' to home. Is that understood?
明白 長官
- Aye, sir. Aye, Sir. - Aye, Sir.
小子 上甲板
Green horn, on deck!
走
On ya go!
遵命 遵命 陸人
Aye, aye, landsman.
湯姆·尼克森 對吧 是的 長官
- Thomas Nickerson, right? - Aye, Sir.
有些人一開始會覺得噁心
Ya know, some feel sick at first.
拉我上去 這是最好的辦法
- Pull me back up! - Best way to square up to King Neptune, Boy.
求你了 拉我上去
Please, bring me up.
好點了嗎
Better now?
長官 非常對不起
Sir, I am so sorry.
你現在有故事寫信回家告訴你母親了
Well, now you got something to write home to your mother about.
我母親葬在史密斯山
My mother's buried up in Smith's Hill,
我爸也是 他
and a stone for my father, too, he was...
他在我出生前就葬身大海了
he was lost at sea before I was born.
給我
Here, give me that.
白鯨現在是你的家人了 是好是壞
The whale's is your family now, Boy, for better or for worse.
壞處多是
For worse mostly.
清理甲板 小子
Swab the deck, Kid!
你離學會捕鯨和航行還差遠了
You're a long way from base to be whaling and sailing.
是 長官
Aye, aye, Captain.
你系錯繩子了 是 長官
- You got that line wrong, Nickerson. - Aye, Captain.
如果有必要我們會訓練到日落
We'll stay at this until sunlight if we have to.
是 長官
Aye, Captain.
魚叉手準備乘船
Harpooners make ready to boat.
雷 動作快點 我的錯
- Need to move quicker, Mr. Ray! - My mistake.
沒有女人玩了 查斯
Ain't no more wee whores, Mr. Chase.
你現在是水手了 哈哈
You're a sailor, now! Yeah!.
幹的不錯 雷
Not bad, Mr. Ray, well done!
要習慣 夥計們 你們得像馬一樣工作
Get used to it, mates, you gotta work like horses.
查斯先生 長官
- Mr. Chase. - Sir.
揚帆
Set stuns'ls.
這樣做好嗎 長官 我們接近洋流
Is that wise, Sir, we're near the Gulf Stream.
看這天氣也還得緩慢前進
Best to be five knots fto even see the weather.
我們落後兩天行程了
We are two days behind.
你得在東風來臨前彌補上時間
You need to make up the time before we catch the east wind.
揚帆
Set stuns'ls.
拴繩 揚帆
Belay that, set stuns'ls.
克芬 鬆開帆 船長要提速
Get her off, Mr. Coffin, the Captain wants speed!
遵命 長官
Aye, Sir.
她老了 但是還能讓我們爽 哈哈
She might be old but she can still blow, boys!
長官 右舷方向有一颶風團 我們需要馬上降帆
Sir, a squall on the starboard route, we need to shorten the sail immediately.
還不行 查斯
Not just yet, Mr. Chase.
長官 我們以8里的速度駛向風暴
Sir, we are headed into a storm of more than 8 knots
而且速度越來越快
and it's movin' faster than that.
讓它來吧 水手們在陸地上呆久變軟弱了
Let it come, the men are soft from months on land, they
他們需要一次洗禮 告訴他們工作開始了
need a good baptism, let them know our work has begun.
如果我們不降帆並駛離 風暴一定會追上我們的
If we don't shorten sail and bear off it'll catch us on the beam.
查斯 我們繼續向前航行
Chase, we will stand on.
勞倫斯 繼續向前 繼續向前 長官
- Mr. Lawrence, hold our course. - Holding course, Sir.
我們這樣前行會追到只差半天的航程
We'll lose half a day running like that.
我們最後能趕上 如果我們的人
We'll scut the end of it, if the men can't
不能應付這樣的狂風 上帝也幫不了我們
handle a gust like this, then God help us all.
固定好一切應付糟糕的天氣
Best secure for heavy weather.
準備好應付天氣 邦德 我們要駛向風暴了
Best prepare for weather, Mr. Bond, we're headed into a squall.
我們必須降帆離開這裏 退下 查斯先生
- We must fall off and run with it. - Stand down, Mr. Chase.
勞倫斯 航向不變 航向不變 長官
- Mr. Lawrence, hold your course. - Holding course, Sir.
降帆 查斯
Shorten the sails, Mr. Chase.
我們要砍下那些帆
We need to cut those sails down!
船掉頭 向陸地開
Turn the ship, head for land!
不 損壞已經造成了
No, the damage is done!
太晚了 太他媽晚了
It's too late, it's too god damned late!
我們會撞上的
We'll be broadsided!
抓牢
Hold on!
小心
Look out!
花花公子
Mr. Joy!
我們要割斷 我知道了 歐文
- We have to cut away the... - I've got it, Owen!
我們要讓船擺正
We have to set her up right!
你說要見我 長官
You wish to see me, Sir.
明天六時 你召集船員
At six bells tomorrow, you will assemble the crew,
告知他們我們將返回楠塔基特維修
inform them that we will be returning to Nantucket for repairs.
然後你向他們道歉你干涉了船長的命令
You will then apologize to them for interfering with a captain's order
今天差點讓船上的每個人都為此喪命
which nearly cost the lives of every man on this ship today.
什麼
What?
返回到港口我會接受你的辭呈
I'll accept your resignation upon our return to port.
就這些
That will be all.
是你下命令楊帆的 長官
It was your order to set stuns'ls, Sir.
命令沒問題 這些人需要鍛煉
That decision was sound, the men needed testing.
你送他們進風暴
- You sent 'em into a storm? - That...
那是幸運不好
was unlucky.
不 這是缺乏航海經驗 責怪運氣只會顯得軟弱
No, it was bad seamanship, and blaming misfortune is just plain weakness.
你他媽的無禮 你知道你在和誰說話嗎
Damn your impertinence! Do you know who you're speaking to?
我是船長喬治·波拉德 波拉德
My name is CAPTAIN George Pollard. POLLARD!
而你查斯先生 無論你衣袖上釘多少白鯨徽章
And you Mr. Chase, no matter how many whale pins you may have on your lapel,
你不過是個農民的兒子
are nothing more than the son of a farmer,
仗勢欺人才當上的長官
who's managed to bullying his way into an officer's tunic.
滾出去
Now, get out!
不帶一桶油回港口是個錯誤 長官
To return to port without a single barrel of oil would be a mistake, Sir.
和名字是波拉德或者查斯沒什麼關係
And not behoove a man whose name is Pollard... or Chase, for that matter.
對我們來說最好是抓緊時間工作
And the best thing for both of us would be t'work all hours God sends us.
把船裝滿油一年之內回到家
Fill this ship with oil, and be home inside a year
然後各自分道揚鑣
and rid of one another as quickly as possible.
相信我 我也迫不及待這樣做
Trust me, I have never been as desirous of that as you.
當然 這由船長來做決定
Of course, that is the Captain's decision.
他們像一對新婚夫婦
They were like a new married couple.
新婚夫婦能容忍對方 梅爾維爾先生
A new married couple tolerate each other, Mr. Melville,
但新婚夫婦也能兩敗俱傷
but a new married couple can also bring down a ship.
你結婚了嗎 梅爾維爾先生 是的
- You married, Mr. Melville? - I am.
上帝仁慈
The Lord have mercy on ya.
第一個孩子也快生了
First child on the way, too.
那你的妻子知道你把所有的積蓄都帶來了
So, does your good wife know that you brought all you have in the world here tonight,
並且給了一個陌生人嗎
and givin' it to a stranger?
不知道 先生 你總讓人吃驚
- No, Sir. - You're full of surprises, aren't you?
那麼 埃塞克斯號沒有回港口
So... the Essex did not return to port.
沒有 她繼續駛向大海
- She did not. - She continued out to sea.
是的 但不久 我們都聽到這個捕鯨人都盼望聽到的吼聲
Yes, she did, but before long, we heard the call this all whale men pray for...
Ho!
噴水
Blows!
是大傢伙 噴水了
A big one! Thar she blows!
公的母的 拉姆斯德爾先生  他們是公的
- White or sperm, Mr. Ramsdell? - Sperm whales they are!
查斯先生  升起船隻
Mr. Chase, hoist and swing boat.
都來甲板
- All Hands! All hands on deck! - All hands on deck!
放船
Lower away!
出海三個月 南大西洋
再加把勁兒
Come on, put your back into it.!
幼年鯨
There's the calf.
幼年鯨 母鯨
- That's the calf? - That's the cow!
乖乖 那是我們的錢
That's our boy! That's the money!
尼克森 使勁
Nickerson! Push!
夠四十桶油了吧 五十桶
- Forty barrels there? - Fifty!
天 他是個大傢伙
Boy, he's a buster!
使勁劃 要不然他要逃了
Take the oars, lads! Quick or he'll god damn run!
劃起來 機靈點 夥計們 機靈點
Pull those oars up! Smartly, lads, smartly!
小心槳端
Mind your oars!
拉姆斯德爾 準備繩 是 長官
- Mr. Ramsdell, prepare the line. - Aye, Sir.
第一頭是我的
The first one's mine.
瞄準她的弱點
Aim her to the free spot!
拉 拉 跟著
Pull! Pull! Stay on him.
夥計們 你們坐上了楠塔基特號第一班雪橇
You're on your first Nantucket sleigh ride, Boys.
地球上最可怕的生物
The most fearsome creature to ever live on this earth.
我的手
My hand!
你得把繩弄濕 尼克森
You need to wet the line, Nickerson.
只剩140英尋的繩子了 查斯先生
A hundred forty fathoms' of line left, Mr. Chase.
只剩80英尋的繩子了 長官
Eighty fathoms' of line left, Sir.
他會把我們拖到水裏的
He's gonna pull us under!
馬修 我要你的繩子 給我繩
- Matthew, I need your line! - Feed the line!
彼得森給我繩子 是的 長官
- Peterson give me the line! - Aye, Sir.
把那繩給我 彼得森 我們只剩60英尋的繩子了 長官
- Give me that line, Mr. Peterson. - We're down to 60 fathoms' of line left, Sir.
20英尋了 查斯先生 鬆開繩
- Twenty fathoms, Mr. Chase! - Tie it off!
快
Go!
彼得森 你來 是 長官
- Peterson, lay on! - Aye, Sir.
還剩多長的繩子
How many fathoms can he draw?
不 不 等等
No, no, no, wait!
歐文 不 不是現在
- Owen! - Oh, no, not yet!
別碰那繩 只剩50英尋了 長官
- Don't touch that line. - Down to 50 fathoms, Sir.
歐文 他媽的 我說了不要動
- Owen! God damn it! - I said don't touch it!
剩30英尋了 花花公子
Thirty fathoms left, Mr. Joy.
剩10英尋了 長官
Ten fathoms left, Sir!
真是漫長的過程
It's been a long drive.
油中的脂肪
Blubber in the oil.
它們要吃掉你的錢了
They're gonna eat your money.
滾開 混賬畜生
Get out of there, you sons of bitches!
- 你拿到了嗎 拿到了 查斯
- You got it? - Got it, Chase.
看起來怎麼樣 不怎麼樣
- How's it lookin'? - Not good.
就這麼多了
That's it.
查斯先生 什麼
- Mr. Chase, Sir? - Yep.
長官 就這麼多了 我們拿不到更多了
That's all of it, Sir, we can't get anymore out.
那就是金礦 夥計們 繼續挖
That's the gold in there, Boys, c'mon, keep diggin'.
我塊頭太大下不去 得找個身材小的
- I'm too big to really go down there. - Then find someone who can.
尼克森 過來小子
Nickerson, come here boy!
嘿 我喊你過來
Hey! I said c'mere!
爬進去
Climb on in with 'im.
來啊 湯姆斯
Come on, Thomas.
這裏面的東西可比它的肉值錢多了
What's in there is worth a HELLEVA lot more than what they're boilin' down.
長官 我不行 對不起 我做不了
Sir, I can't, I'm sorry. I can't.
你自己進去或者我讓你睡在裏面
You get down there, or I'll have you sleep down there.
你用牙齒把這東西咬住 小子
You best put that between your teeth, Boy.
它裏面臭得很
It tastes worse than the Devil's asshole down there.
謝謝
Thank you.
抱歉 尼克森 我的枕頭送你
- Sorry. - Here, Nickerson, take my pillow with ya!
下去
Down ya go.
一個人在裏面能更瞭解自己
A man gets to know himself down there.
他們有送你進一頭鯨的頭裏面嗎 沒有 他們饒了我
- Did they ever send you into a whale's head? - No, I was spared.
那裏面才是寶藏所在
Well, that's where the treasure is.
我永遠都不會忘記那第一頭
I'll never forget that first bull.
47桶油 當然 幸福很短暫
Forty-seven barrels... of course, the happiness was short lived.
那片水域沒有鯨魚可捕了
The waters had all been fished out?
是的 所以我們向更遠處前進
That they had. So, we headed further out.
在那一個月之後
It was a month around the Horn.
離開了南大西洋
Left the South Atlantic behind with a sliver of hope
期望情況會變好
that things would change for the better.
但到了太平洋事實上沒有改善
But making the Pacific didn't improve our lot.
太他媽難看到鯨了
Whale sightings were TOO damn scarce.
將近一年後脾氣衝動的船長
After nearly a year at sea the temperaments of our captain.
和大副都變的沮喪
And our first mate grew more strained.
船長波拉德幾乎整天待在船艙裏
Captain Pollard spent most days and nights in his cabin,
害怕看到船員無法交代
afraid to look his crew in the eye.
我們的倉儲大半還空著
Our hold was almost empty.
凝視著我們皮毛的成果只會提醒我們
To gaze upon our paltry efforts only served as a reminder
離回家還有很長一段路
that we were a long way from going home.
阿塔卡梅斯 厄瓜多爾
我聽不懂 說英語
I don't talk that talk. Speak English?
他們在說鯨油
They're talking whale oil.
牧師堅持要我們寫信回家告知我們的情況
他覺得這些信幫得了誰
那些寡婦
船都沒有的船主
你還要像這樣生活多久 船長
寫信給西班牙 為你和你的船長 祈求原諒
沒人可以阻止發生的一切
誰會相信呢 沒有人 顧主不會相信的
這麼多年你用油換來錢裝滿他們的口袋
長官
Capitбn.
打擾了 當地人告訴我你的航程遇到阻礙了 長官
Excuse me, the locals told me that your voyage was waylaid, Sir.
埃塞克斯號船長 喬治·波拉德
Captain George Pollard, the Essex.
聖瑪麗亞號船長 克萊門特佩萊斯
Capitбn Clemente Pelaez, the Santa Maria.
給大伙來一杯
Would you buy a colleague a drink?
老樣子 喬治 是的 船長
- Same as always, George. - Yes, Captain
壞運氣
Bad luck, huh?
那有多遠
How far out?
遠到只有傻子才會去
Far enough for only a fool to go.
那是多遠
How far would that be?
一千里格 在赤道附近
A thousand leagues along the Equator...
近海區域
in offshore grounds.
鯨都在那兒
Were there whales there?
多到你做夢不敢想
More than you've ever dreamt.
成百上千 密密麻麻望不到邊
Hundreds... fields of flukes as far as the eye can see.
他們原本一天就夠裝滿3000桶油
They could fill up 3000 barrels in the space of a day.
什麼意思 "原本"
What do you mean, "Could have"?
要不是那裏的那頭怪物
If it weren't for that demon...
一頭鯨
a whale.
白如蠟石
White as alabaster,
一百英尺長
a hundred feet long,
我的六名船員因為它喪命
sent six of my crew to their graves,
剩下的我們 只會讓人想起那頭怪物
and the rest of us, something to remember him by.
那頭白鯨 他跳舞給你看 還逗你玩嗎
Now, this white whale, did he dance a jig and pick your pocket, as well?
謝謝
Thank you.
你相信他的鬼話
Do you believe that?
我們馬上出發 趕上南風帶
We set sail now, catch the south easterlies,
這是我們絕佳的機會 填飽肚子 我們有機會在半年內回家
this is by our best time, fill our belly, we can be home in six months.
你怎麼看 查斯先生
What say you, Mr. Chase?
沒必要再忍受這種困境了
No need to endure our predicament for a moment longer than necessary.
同意
Amen to that.
Amen.
同意
貪婪影響了船長和大副
Greed took hold of our Captain and the first mate.
然後我們沿著赤道前往一千里格外的
So, we headed out... a thousand leagues along the Equator...
但是沒想到 傳言流開了
but with no agenda, speculation began.
說鯨都藏在那裏
This is where the whales are gonna hide.
那是我們能到達的最遠的地方
It was as far from land as we could possibly go.
但是我們要追捕他們
But we hunted them down.
幾個世紀前 水手們害怕會航到地球邊界
Centuries before, sailors feared sailing off the edge of the earth,
但我們是駛向理智的邊緣
but we were headed for the edge of sanity.
信任給猜疑讓位
Trust gave way to doubt...
期望消除迷信
hope to blind superstition.
船長 船員在議論
Cap'n, the men are talking.
這很正常
That's what men do.
他們對你航行這麼遠的決定不滿
They aren't happy with your decision to sail out this far.
你糾正他們的觀點了嗎
Well, did you correct them?
你提醒他們我們的目標是用鯨油裝滿這艘船
Did you remind them of our purpose to fill this ship with whale oil
如果那裏有成百上千頭鯨 為什麼不去呢
and if the whales ARE a thousand leagues out, then that is where we go?
表哥 拜託了 這太瘋狂了
Cousin, please, this is madness.
你被那人影響了
You have let yourself be influenced by that man.
你必須把船調頭
You must turn this ship back.
我建議你回去 消除他們的疑慮
I suggest you go back down, reassure the men, the leader,
以後別再仗著家庭身份來找我
and don't ever, ever abuse the privilege of family with me again...
克芬先生
Mr. Coffin.
出海第十四個月
怎麼了
What is it?
聽 查斯先生
- Listen... - Mr. Chase.
我看到些白柱 哪裏
- I see some white water. - Where?
左舷
Port side!
你看到什麼了嗎
You see anything?
出船 出船
- Lower away! - Lower away!
那頭掛物要完蛋了
The Devil'll take the Mexican ground.
用力刺他 刺他
Stick him hard! Stick him!
一直向前 彼得森
Straight ahead, Peterson.
別人他咬了船槳 夥計們
Don't let him chew the oars, Boys.
看著點
Back to it!
那頭鯨 是的
- The whale? - Yes.
傳言是真的 是的
- So, it's true. - Yes.
可惜是真的
Too much is true.
全速
Full pressure!
邦德先生 後退4碼 載具放下來
Mr. Bond, back to 4 yards, lower the tackle!
遵命 長官
Aye, Sir.
勞倫斯先生 駛向下風口的鯨群
Mr. Lawrence, take us leeward headed straight for the school.
馬上 長官
Right, Sir.
熱焦油 長官 我們會找到他的
- Hot tar, Sir. - We'll find him.
我們接近背部了
We're close to black skin.
靠近她
Sneak up on her!
她是我們的了
She's ours, Lads.
那是什麼 勞倫斯先生
What was that, Mr. Lawrence?
查斯先生
Mr. Chase.
媽的
God damn it.
找勞倫斯過來
Find Mr. Lawrence...
找勞倫斯去抽水
Get Mr. Lawrence to man the pumps!
他在哪兒
Where is he?
左舷船頭
Port bow!
給我最大的魚叉
Get me the biggest tines we have.
他想來一戰
He wants a fight.
我從來沒過鯨這麼做 勞倫斯 掌舵
- I never seen a whale do that. - Mr. Lawrence, take the wheel.
拉姆斯德爾 把繩子另一頭繫在前桅
Mr. Ramsdell, secure the other end of the line to the foremast.
遵命 長官
Aye, Sir.
只要我還活著 他是我的
As I live and breathe, he's mine.
當心
Look out!
船長
Cap'n...
埃塞克斯號 它在傾斜
The Essex, it's listing.
幫我調頭
Help me turn around.
勇敢點 在這 過來 尼克森
- That's it, be brave. - Here! Full ahead, Mr. Nickerson.
查斯先生
Mr. Chase.
一頭鯨撞壞了船
A whale threw her, it stove the ship.
什麼
What?
我們失去了伊斯頓和山本
We lost Easton and Sanborn.
水泵沒用了 長官
The pumps are useless, Sir.
準備棄船 我們不能劃著回去
- Prepare to abandon ship. - We can't row away home!
我們必須從船上帶走必要的東西
We have to strip from the sails and jimmy-rig something.
遵命 長官
Aye, Sir.
帶上盡可能多的水和食物
Get as much food and water as you can carry.
我們需要你們能找到的任何一滴水
We're gonna need all the fresh water you can find.
我們盡可能待在一塊
We stick together as much as we can.
查普爾先生 儲備物
Mr. Chappel, the provisions!
帶上盡可能多的食物
Take as much food as you can carry.
清理道路
Make way!
拿住 儲備食物
- Got it? - Hard tack and stock!
帶上那些蠟燭 船帆下來了
- Grab the candles there! - Lower away!
拿上那些儲物櫃
Take those tack lockers.
拉上去
Pull her up!
快 尼克森
Come on, Nickerson!
當心
Pace yourself!
抓住手 我拉到你了 拉他上來
- Grab the hand! I got you! - Get 'im up!
離油遠點
Gotta get away from the oil.
尼克森 查斯先生在哪兒 他剛才還在這 長官
- Nickerson! Where is Mr. Chase? - He was just here, Sir.
查斯先生
Mr. Chase!
查斯
Mr. Chase, Sir!
大副在哪兒 離遠點
- Where is the first mate? - Away!
查斯
Mr. Chase, Sir!
他在那兒 他在那兒 他在那兒
There he is! There he is! There he is!
這裏 查斯在那兒
- Over there! - There's Mr. Chase!
查斯先生
Mr. Chase!
抓住他了
We got him.
我們去釣魚是吧
Goin' fishin', are we?
都準備好了 花花公子
Clear and loaded, Mr. Joy.
退後 不然我們會和她一起下沉的
Back away, or she'll take us down with her.
南美洲以西 2000海里
船長 我們的食物怎麼辦
Captain, what about our provisions?
每人每天兩盎司的硬麵餅
Two ounces of hardtack a day per man...
和半杯水
and half a cup of water.
不夠的
We can't live on that.
是他
It's he!
對 是他
Yeah, it's him all right.
你騙不了我 查斯先生
You don't fool me, Mr. Chase.
克芬先生 是嗎
- Mr. Coffin. - That right?
你帶我們來這的 你知道的
You put us here, you know you put us here.
嘿 放下槍 放下手槍
- Hey! Put it down. - Put the pistol down!
告訴我你害怕了
Say you're scared!
克芬先生 放下槍
Mr. Coffin, put the pistol down!
你清楚食物和水耗盡後會怎樣
You know what happens when the food and water runs out!
按船長說的做 克芬先生
Do as the Captain says, Coffin!
我只是想看到
I just want to see
陸人害怕 克芬 放下槍
- the landsman scared. - Coffin, put the pistol down!
這是命令 按照船長說的做
- That's an order! - Do as the Captain says! Now!
說啊 亨利
- Say it! - Henry.
說啊 說啊
Say it! Say it!
亨利 放下槍
Henry! Put the pistol down.
Henry, put it down.
亨利 放下槍
然後向東
So, east it was,
按來的路線回去
back in the direction we'd come,
頂著烈日靠著一個指南針
With only the sun and a compass.
所有的方向都看起來一樣
All directions looked the same.
我們的期望是靠著西風帶漂到復活島
Our hope was to catch the westerlies to Easter Island,
3000英里的距離
a journey of 3,000 miles.
過了12天我們漂到了南方
For 12 days we've drifted south.
6度緯度
Six degrees latitude.
離復活島差了十萬八千里
Not one mile closer to Easter Island.
我們被詛咒了
We are cursed.
當我們趕上風帶我們會彌補上的
We'll make up for it when we catch the variables.
我們會趕上的
We'll catch 'em.
抓牢了 船長
Hold on, Captain!
花花公子 帆繩纏住了
Mr. Joy, the halyard's jammed.
花花公子 抓住它 花花公子
Mr. Joy! Grab at it, Mr. Joy!
馬修
Matthew!
馬修 發生了什麼 發生了什麼
Matthew, okay, what happened? What happened?
你在這幹什麼 讓我看看
- What are you doing here? - Let me take a look.
不 不 不 讓我看看
- No, no, no. - Let me take a look.
我沒事 我沒事
I'm fine, I'm fine.
放鬆 我知道 讓我看一眼
Just relax, I know, I know, let me take a look.
我被擊中頭部了 我沒事 好嗎
I'm hit on the head, it's good, right?
給他些水 我不需要什麼水
- Give him some water! - I don't need any water!
給他他媽的一些水喝
Give him some God damned water.
不 不 我不需要水 我沒事
No, no, no, I don't need water, I'm fine.
拿著
Take that, take it!
沒事
I gotcha, I gotcha!
沒事的 你會沒事的
All right, you'll be all right.
嘿 你們在看什麼 我沒事
Hey, what are you all looking at, I'm fine.
波拉德船長 我裝的
Cap'n Pollard, this is fiddle.
我忽悠你們的 聽見了嗎
This is God damn fiddle, ya hear me?
歐文 在
- Owen. - Yeah.
我沒事 我沒事
I'm fine, all right, I'm fine.
我沒事 離開這
- Thank you. - I'm fine! Get out of here!
他沒事
He is good.
我們走
Let's go.
為什麼在死人身上浪費水
Why waste water on a dead man?
他們從小一起航海 情同手足
Fancy men who know each other, sailed together since childhood.
你告訴我
Now, tell me,
你會坐等著看你的兄弟死去嗎
could you just sit there and watch your own brother die?
簡單的算術問題 查普爾先生
It's simply a matter of numbers, Mr. Chappel.
水不夠我們所有人用
There's not enough for all of us.
為什麼在死人身上浪費水
Why waste water on a dead man?
為什麼浪費水
Why waste water...
Why waste water?
為什麼浪費水
為什麼在死人身上浪費水
Why waste water on a dead man?
尼克森先生
Mr. Nickerson?
為什麼在死人身上浪費水 你還好嗎 先生
- Why waste water on a dead man? - Are you all right, Sir.
我不能 不能什麼
- I cannot. - Cannot what?
不 你 你 你知道足夠多了 你瞭解夠多了
No, you... you... you have enough, you have more than enough.
但是 先生 我們都講到這兒了
But, Sir! We've come so far.
我們必須善始善終 我們有約定的 先生
- We have come to an end. - We have an agreement, Sir.
拿著錢離開 這是魔鬼的交易
Take the money and leave! You've a devil's bargain!
不 長官 魔鬼喜歡隱藏秘密
No, Sir, the devil loves his unspoken secrets...
特別是那些蠶食人的靈魂的秘密
especially those that fester in a man's soul.
你的秘密是什麼
What's yours?
我不是一個好作家
I'm not a great writer.
我不是霍索恩
I'm not Hawthorne.
從我學寫作以來
After my first hearing of Odysseus,
這個故事一直困擾著我
this tale has haunted me.
它消耗著我
It consumes me.
我害怕如果我不寫這個故事
I fear if I do not write it,
我會再也沒辦法寫作
I should never write again.
還有什麼
What else?
我害怕如果我寫這個故事
I fear if I DO write it,
寫出來的不如故事精彩
that it will not be as good as it should be.
繼續講這個故事 先生
Continue the story, Sir...
為了彼此
for the both of us.
困住的第34天
傳過去
Pass that down.
給
Here.
我們感謝你 主 賜予我們的食物
We thank thee, Lord, for this is our food...
賜予我們的光 健康 和所有美好的東西
for light, good health, with every good.
那裏
There.
陸地
Land!
陸地 歐文 陸地
Land, Owen! Land!
陸地 陸地 陸地
Land! Land! Land!
划船 快
Row! Get 'way! Get 'way!
划船
Row!
停下 停下 停下
Hold fast! Hold fast! Hold fast!
查斯 什麼東西 長官
Mr.Chase, what is it, Sir?
查斯 那是什麼怪物 你怎麼停下了
Mr. Chase, what the devil is it, why have you stopped?
他一直在跟著我們 什麼
- He's been following us. - What?
那裏什麼都沒有 查斯先生
There's nothin' out there, Mr. Chase.
那裏什麼都沒有 長官
There ain't nothin' out there, Sir.
長官 你在幹什麼
Sir, what are you doing?
他在哪兒
Where is he?
這可能是迪西島
It could be Ducie Island.
沒有地圖 指南針 象限儀 沒辦法確認
Without a map, compass or quadrant there's no way to be certain.
我們晝夜都亮著火
We will keep fires going night and day,
但願過往的船隻注意到我們的濃煙
hope a passing ship catches sight of our smoke.
這是我想讓你們看的
This is what I wanted you to see.
他們肯定在這很長時間了
They've been here a long time, for no doubt...
一定也在等船隻
waiting for a ship.
但是沒有船來過
But no ship came.
沒有船會來
No ship is going to come.
如果我們呆在這 我們會死
If we stay, we die.
你們覺得如果鳥兒過來看到
How long do you think it would take to trust the birds
自己的蛋被吃了會多久不再過來
to stop coming here once they see their eggs eaten?
這是知道自己將要死去的好處
It's a privilege to know the moment of one's death in advance.
可以為此準備
And to be able to prepare for it...
離家太遠的詛咒
a curse to be so far from home...
或者有機會說再見但沒機會和解
or a chance to say goodbyes, without a chance to make peace...
或者報仇的機會
or a chance to settle scores.
但是 我們之間清楚了
But alas, at least those are settled between us,
船長
Cap'n?
什麼船長
Captain of what?
埃塞克斯號沉沒了不是你的責任
The Essex was lost and no fault o'yours.
我該受譴責 你不是船長
- I was as much to blame... - You were not the Captain!
你天生就是幹這活的料
You were born to do this job.
我只是生下來只能幹這個
I was just born into it.
我們幹了什麼 你覺得 喬治
What we do, do ya think, George?
我們幹了什麼冒犯了上帝 讓他這麼不開心
What offense did we give God to upset him so?
冒犯上帝的是那些白鯨
The only creature to have offended God here is the whale.
不是我們
Not us?
不是我們的傲慢 我們的貪婪 看我們現在在哪兒
Not our arrogance, our greed? Look where we find ourselves.
我們是上帝按自己喜好創造出來的高級生物
We are supreme creatures made in God's own likeness.
我們是地球上的主宰
We're earthly kings,
我們要環航我們居住的星球
whose business it is to circumnavigate the planet bestowed to us.
將自然屈服於我們的意志
And to bend nature to OUR will.
我們經歷了這麼多你還覺得主宰一切嗎
You really feel like an earthly king after everything that we've been through?
我們什麼都不是 我們是微粒 灰塵 但是我們
- We're nothing... we're specks... dust. - But we're...
拂曉時朝太陽方向行駛
We sail into the sun at dawn.
如果我們要死 死在上帝的光輝裏
If we are to die, with God's grace.
讓我們像男人一樣死去
Let us die as men.
我們準備好了嗎 維克斯先生 是的 長官
- Are we ready, Mr. Weeks? - Aye, Sir.
查普爾先生
Mr. Chappel.
萊特先生 我不能 長官
- Mr. Wright. - I can't do it, Sir.
我 洛克斯 維克斯
Me, Locks and Weeks...
我們留下來
we're stayin'.
準備出發 馬修
Ready to go, Matthew?
我來幫你一把 有什麼用
- I'll give you a hand here... - What's the point?
你聽見我說的嗎 不 我們一起回家 一起回家
- You hear me? - No, we're goin' home, we're goin' home.
沒用的
There's no point.
走吧
Just go.
媽的 馬修
God damn it, Matthew.
沒事的
It's all right.
我回家立馬派一艘船過來接你
I'll send a boat for you the minute we get back.
然後我們回到楠塔基特玩牌 好嗎
And we'll play cards back in Nantucket, all right?
好 一言為定 好
- Yeah, it's a deal. - Good.
你要我幫你打開水壺嗎
You want me to open that for ya?
我能行的
Naw, I think I'll manage.
上帝保佑你 兄弟
God be with you, Brother.
也保佑你
And you.
彼得森
Brother Peterson?
你一起跟我們走吧 彼得森先生
- Y'all comin' with us? - Mr. Peterson.
和邦德一起登船走吧
Why don't you come on our boat with Mr. Bond.
困住的第48天
在哪兒 他在哪兒
Where... where is he?
波拉德
Pollard.
勞倫斯先生 勞倫斯先生 醒醒
Mr. Lawrence, Mr. Lawrence, wake up.
另一條船去哪兒了
Where has the other boat gone?
波拉德 波拉德 船長波拉德
- Pollard! Pollard! - Captain Pollard!
- Pollard! Pollard! - Cap'n Pollard!
波拉德 波拉德 船長波拉德
波拉德 船長
- Pollard! - Captain!
波拉德
Pollard!
休息會兒
Get some rest.
本傑明 你在幹什麼
Benjamin, what are you doing?
他死了
He's dead.
把他丟海裏 長官
Throwing him overboard, Sir.
看著我 看著我 本傑明
Look at me, look at me Benjamin.
沒有理智的水手會丟棄也許會救自己一命的東西
No right minded sailor discards what might yet save him.
聽我說 孩子 聽我說
Listen to me, Boy, listen to me.
他能救我們
He can help us.
我的上帝 我們神聖的
My God, our heavenly...
這些生物每日祈盼著食物
Thy creatures wait On Thee for daily food.
決定了
So it was decided.
我們準備了屍體
We prepared the body.
我們去除了內臟
We removed the organs.
分割了他的四肢
Separated his limbs from his body.
從骨頭上切下了所有的肉
And cut all the flesh from the bones.
然後
After which...
我們拼起了屍塊
we closed body.
然後把屍體縫起來
And then we sewed it up...
盡我們所能
as decently as we could...
然後扔到了海裏
and committed it to the sea.
我們先吃了心臟
We ate the heart first.
你有意見
You judge me.
不
No.
那個
There... there...
說完了
it's done.
It is out.
說完了
你從未告訴過任何人
You never told anyone?
沒有
No.
包括你的妻子
Not even your wife?
你覺得如果她知道我做的罪孽
Do you think she could ever love me,
她還會愛我嗎
if she knew the abominations I had committed?
不 她還會愛你的
Yes, she would.
如果你和我相遇的時候告訴我
And if you had told me this story when we met,
我今天還會是你的妻子
I would still wear your ring today.
那個男孩的勇敢
The strength of that boy,
還在你內心
still lives in you.
我看得出
I see that...
即使你自己不覺察
even if you don't.
你可以說完你的故事了 親愛的
You can finish your story now, My Love.
嘿
Look...
坐起來
Sit up.
聽著
Listen.
媽的
Damn thing.
我們還有些水
We still got a few drops of the water left.
別放棄 我們要回家了
Don't ya quit on me, we're goin' home.
你還有家人在嗎
Do you have a family...
查斯先生
back home, Mr. Chase?
有的 我的妻子
Yeah, I have wife.
對 還有一個兒子和一個女兒
Yes, and a son or a daughter.
困住的第71天 南美以西1200海里
好
Very well.
船長 我們重新抽籤
Cap'n, we'll draw again.
我們不會這麼做
We'll do no such thing.
我們重新抽 拉姆斯德爾先生
- We'll draw again. - Mr. Ramsdell,
你要用這槍來指揮
you will assume command of this vessel.
你明白
Ya got that?
你是我們的船長 你的船員需要你
You're our cap'n, your men need you.
船員沒事的
The men will be fine.
拜託了 拜託了
Please. Please. Please.
亨利 讓我們再抽籤
- Henry... - Let us go again.
這是命令
It is an order.
如果你做不到
If you cannot do it,
把槍給其他人
pass the pistol to another man.
我們在赤道無風帶幾周了
We were weeks in the Doldrums.
太平洋那片區域遠比海洋枯竭
That part of the Pacific is more desert than ocean.
太陽炙熱
The sun beating down...
我害怕
My fear...
我能想到的是
All I could think about...
所有人都會死而我是最後一個活著的
was that everyone would die and I'd be the last left alive.
查斯只知道我們離陸地還有800英里
Well, as best as Mr. Chase could tell, we were still 800 miles from land.
查斯先生
Mr. Chase.
船長波拉德
Cap'n Pollard.
很高興見到你
Very happy to see you.
我們生存下來沒什麼值得高興
Very little happiness in our survival.
我們也是 長官
Nor in ours, Sir.
巴爾齊萊號
Barzillai?
另一艘船
The third boat?
他們不見了 幾天不見了
They're gone, they've been gone for days.
我估計他們迷失了 長官
I'm afraid they're lost, Sir.
查斯先生 你為這個準備好了
Mr. Chase, you are prepared for this.
不過是頭白鯨
It's just a whale.
那裏 投茅
There! Throw the lance!
投啊
Throw it!
Throw it, drown the lad!
投啊
Throw it!
就是現在 投茅啊
Do it! Now! Throw the lance!
你為什麼不投
Why didn't you throw it?
你他媽是個傻子
You're a damn fool.
洋流把我們拆散了
The current drew us apart...
那是我們最後一次見到船長波拉德的鯨船
and that was the last we would see of Captain Pollard's whale boat.
困住的第87天
一艘船
A boat!
前方有一艘船
A boat on the forward bow!
上帝仁慈
May god have mercy.
困住的第90天 1821年2月18日
查斯先生
Mr. Chase.
父親
Father...
別丟下我 父親
don't leave me, Father.
嘿 長官
Hey, Sir.
查斯先生 長官 看 看 長官
Mr. Chase. Sir. Look. Look, Sir.
長官
Sir.
看 那裏
Look. Out there.
他們來了
They're coming.
他們來救我們了
They're coming for us.
我們在那裏被救了
We were rescued there, off the Isle of Mбs Afuera, Chile,
埃塞克斯號沉船90天後
ninety days after the sinking of the Essex.
他們給我們一些衣服和皮革吃
They gave us some old clothes... leathers, too.
起先感覺很難吃
It was hard to eat at first... strange.
他們盡力照顧我們
They looked after us as best they could,
然後他們找到了可以帶我們回家的一艘船
then we found a ship that could carry us home.
回家又花了三個月
That voyage took another three months.
1821年6月11日 楠塔基特港口
全島的人好像都過來看我們回來
It looked like the whole Island turned out to see us return.
但是沒有歡呼 只有沉寂
But there were no cheers... only silence.
他們看我們的樣子像是看到鬼 幽靈
They looked at us like we were... apparitions... phantoms.
我們沒有對任何人說起我們生存的細節
We'd said nothing of the details of our survival to anyone.
但是我猜他們知道我們的困境
But I wondered if they somehow knew of our privations.
也許他們只是好奇
Maybe they were just curious.
我保證過的 不是嗎
I promised, didn't I?
天啊
God.
嘿 寶貝 你是誰啊
Hey, Sweetie! Who is this?
菲比安
Phebe Ann.
菲比安·查斯
Phebe Ann Chase.
他是你的父親
It's your Daddy.
嘿 寶貝
Hey, Sweetie.
他是你的父親
It's your Daddy.
當然還是有人找上他
Of course they couldn't leave him alone.
查斯先生和他的妻子往家走了不久
Mr. Chase and his wife had scarcely walked a block towards home
他就被攔下來並帶回了海事辦公室
when he was stopped and made to return to the Maritime Office.
生意上的事還有疑問
There were business matters still in question.
對於這件事
So, to the matter...
因為我們此次航線造成了巨大的人員和財產損失
Due to the significant loss of life and property on our voyage,
將會有一場聽證會
it seems there will be an inquiry.
作為船長和大副 我們需要交待事實經過
And, as Captain and first mate, we will be expected to give account of what happened.
是的 當然
Yes, of course.
我就這件事和船主和我父親討論過
And, having discussed this with the ship owners and... my father,
顯然完全交待經過會有後果
it is clear that full disclosure will have ramifications...
對整個行業有可怕的後果
terrible ramifications for whole industry.
一頭白鯨弄沉了埃塞克斯號
That a whale brought down the Essex.
但這是事實
But it's the truth.
如果保險商和投資人開始擔心
If the insurance houses and investors were to start worrying about...
海怪把船弄沉
sea monsters sinking ships,
水手們很難活下來
sailors drawing lots to survive...
我們在石油行業 所有人
We are in the oil business... all of us.
在任何一個行業成功的機率一定要比失敗的風險要高
And as in any business the probability of success must always be greater the risk incurred.
那麼 你有什麼建議 喬治
So, what are you suggesting, George?
你就說船擱淺了
That you say that the ship ran aground.
那是個謊言 並且說船員是淹死的
- That's a lie. - And that the men that died drowned.
那也是個謊言
That's another lie.
想想吧 他們會讓你當船長
Think on it... they will make you captain.
那個我是有書面保證的
Oh! That pledge I already have in writing.
那個前提是你帶回一船的鯨油
Only on the condition you bring home a ship full of oil.
這麼做會確保你這件事
This way it's guaranteed.
你會變成有錢人
You would be a wealthy man.
查斯不再是陸人的名字 而是有記錄的
The name Chase need no longer be a landsman's name, but an established name
屬於楠塔基特島偉大家族的名字
that belongs among the great families of Nantucket.
你要我為了功名掩蓋發生的一切
You want me to whitewash what happened for profit?
我們是要你務實些
We're asking you to be pragmatic.
埃塞克斯號是被一頭白鯨撞沉的
The Essex was stoved by a white whale.
我們倖存下來的在裝備不良的捕鯨船上
And those of us that survived in ill-equipped whale boats
只能靠犯下罪孽才能存活
had to commit abominations in order to survive.
我們回來後 又被指望傳播公然露骨的謊言
And on our return, we're expected to spread barefaced lies,
好讓你們這些楠塔基特島島船主們
so that you, the ship owners of Nantucket,
賺錢晚上再睡得安穩覺嗎
might line your pockets and sleep well at night?
我不會掩蓋真相
Well, I will not embroil the truth.
喬治 你也不應該
Nor should you, George.
我最後一次見他
That last time I saw him...
查斯先生 長官
Mr. Chase, Sir.
我說不出我想說的話
I couldn't find the right words to say what I wanted.
湯姆斯
Thomas.
也許我沒什麼想說的
Perhaps there ARE no words.
我 我要去法爾茅斯了
I'm... I'm gonna be on my way to Falmouth, and...
那個
it's...
那個 很榮幸 長官
it's... it's been an honor, Sir,
能夠服務於您
to serve with you.
是我的榮幸 尼克森先生
The honor has been mine, Mr. Nickerson.
拿著
Take it.
祝你好運 湯姆斯
Good luck out there, Thomas.
謝謝 長官
Thank you, Sir.
第二天喬治·波拉德被召喚到聽證會
Next day George Pollard was called before the inquiry.
先生們 船長喬治·波拉德
Gentlemen, Captain George Pollard.
楠塔基特所有重要人物都在那兒
All the important men of Nantucket were there...
這是慣例
it was a formality.
日安 船長 請坐
Good day to you, Captain, please sit down.
事實是
For the record then.
埃塞克斯號是在厄瓜多爾以西被一頭1200多米長的白鯨撞沉的
The Essex was stoved by a white whale 12 hundred meters west of Ecuador.
就像歐文·查斯說的那樣
It was as if Owen Chase himself had spoken.
他告訴了他們真相
He told them the truth.
船長波拉德的良心發現了
Cap'n Pollard's conscience was clear...
但那場聽證會是個恥辱
but the inquiry was a sham.
至於那頭白鯨 他們再也沒有找到
over the white whale... they never found it.
他再一次出航但在夏威夷擱淺
He ran a second ship aground off of Hawaii...
兩次詛咒
twice cursed.
再也沒有出航過
Never sailed again.
歐文·查斯
And Owen Chase?
他說到做到
He was a man of his word.
他派了一艘船去了杜斯特島
First, he sent a boat back to Ducie Island.
花花公子已經死了
Mr. Joy had passed...
但是其他人居然還都活著
but the other three were incredibly still alive.
然後呢
And then?
他帶著家人搬到了新貝德福德
Then he packed up his family and moved to New Bedford...
去重新開始生活
to start over...
在一家商店
in a merchant...
完成自己的人生旅程
sailing his own terms.
你用錢換到故事了 梅爾維爾先生
Well, you certainly got your money's worth, Mr. Melville.
這二月的夜晚真是一年中最漫長的
These February nights are the longest of the year.
你們都可以休息了 我不行
- Well, you can both rest now. - Leave me...
我還有一段時間不能休息
I shall not be resting for some time.
為什麼
Why?
你得到了你的故事 情節都有了
Ya got your story there, and your plot is all there.
也許我想要的不是情節
Maybe it wasn't a plot I was after.
不是 那是什麼
No, what then?
你今晚給我的其他東西
Something else you've given me tonight.
是什麼
What is that?
敢於去別人不敢去的地方的勇氣
The courage to go where... one does not want to go.
梅爾維爾先生
Mr. Melville,
你聽到的 我告訴你的
what you've heard, what I've told you,
是否都會成為你書中的一部分
will it all be of service to your book?
這會是部虛構的小說 尼克森先生
It will be a work of fiction, Mr. Nickerson,
受真實事件啟發
inspired by truth,
但我不覺得我會用全部事實
but I don't believe I'll feel the need to use all of it.
謝謝 給
- Thank you. - Here...
拿著這個
take that with you.
不 錢是給你的 我堅持
No, the money is for you, I insist.
我堅持你要收下
I insist you keep it.
我堅持這談話裏還是有一個人是清醒的
And I insist that one person in this conversation is sober.
該回馬薩諸塞州皮茨菲爾德了
So, it's back to Pittsfield, Massachusetts.
祝你好運
Well, good luck.
謝謝
Thank you.
你知道嗎
Ya know...
我聽說賓夕法尼亞州一個人最近在地上鑽了一個洞
I heard a man from Pennsylvania drilled a hole in the ground recently,
發現了油
and found oil.
不會是真的吧
That can't be true.
我也聽說過
I heard it, too.
地上的油
Oil from ground.
真想不到
Fancy that.
赫爾曼·梅爾維爾 1850年完成了他的小說
一年後白鯨記發表
對於白鯨記納撒尼爾·霍桑盛讚它會成為美國偉大的作品
導演：朗·霍華德 翻譯：閒著沒事幹的MT 隨便改